Rahul Bishnoi

Bengaluru, Karnataka +91-8306829458 rahulbishnoi3636@gmail.com

Summary

I am 3rd year undergrad student doing B.Tech in CSE, having experience in many fields of Computer Science such as Software Development, Natural Language and Processing, Graphics, AI, Networking.

For the last one year i am completely obsessed with blockchain and i am learning more and more about it daily through all kind of channels. I am also a bounty hunter at gitcoin and i have done plenty of bounties there primarily related to blockchain development.

I am contributing towards blockchain(ethereum to be precise) daily through one way or another (by doing issues, hackathons, interacting with community) and hope to see it become the internet of value one day.

Profile Links

Gitcoin: https://gitcoin.co/profile/nanspro

Github: https://github.com/nanspro

Technical Writing: https://gist.github.com/nanspro

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/rahul-bishnoi-159176172/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/nanspr0

Education

International Institute of Information Technology,

Bachelor's in Computer Science

Transferred - July 2019

Jaipur National University, Jaipur, Rajasthan

Bachelors in Computer Science

Graduating - July 2021

Languages

English Proficient Hindi Native

Hobbies & Interests

I am interested in ethereum and blockchains. I like to do multi tasking and always take up a lot of projects are once and then try to complete them on time, it helps in pushing my limits.

I love immersing myself in other worlds whether it be watching movie on big screen or playing open world games on my PS4. My favorite all time games are Skyrim and GTA series beacuse of their vast interactive world.

I love progressive, psychdelic, metal rock music.

Besides these i want to travel to different countries to visit beautiful places, interacting with local people. I have not done that because i want to earn some money first and that is why i am holding ether which i receive from bounties:)

Employment History

Ethereum Foundation, Osaka, Osaka

Devcon Scholar July 2019 - Present

Selected as a Devcon V Scholar amongst 50 other candidates from around the world to participate in the Ethereum Foundation's blockchain and cryptocurrency programming. Through the leadership program, I accomplished the following:

- Earned a full scholarship to attend the program in Osaka, Japan
- Developed blockchain 101, theory, and system design skills and completed program's curriculum
- Networked with Ethereum ecosystem leaders and learned how various firms apply blockchain technology to their services and products
- Earned a blockchain program certification

The Vantage Project, New Delhi, Delhi

Blockchain Researcher August 2019 - Present

I am researching different blockchain communities to come up with technical proposals which will be submitted by vantage project after some proofreading and editing.

The comunities i am gonna focus on are: Interchain, Numerai, Zilliquia, Civic

koinearth, Bengaluru, Karnataka

Blockchain Developer

May 2019 - July 2019

I worked upon sidechains and interoperability between two different blockchains. I connected two quorum based networks using bridge to transfer assets them and then made a generic bridge to connect any two ethereum based networks for ERC20 transfers.

During my initial days i also looked upon hyperledger fabric and sawtooth-ethereum(seth). Due to limitation of rpc calls such as eth_sendRawTransaction we decided that it is not feasible to use it for our needs at the moment and hence we moved on with quorum but i learned a great deal about enterprise based blockchains.

In my final days i had to understand chainlink and provable to come up with analysis and see if they can use it to verify information from external APIs on fabric blockchain for their supplychain product.

Gitcoin

Bounty Hunter August 2018 - Present

I have contributed to many open source blockchain related projects and got paid for them via gitcoin. Here is the link to my profile where all my projects can be seen http://gitcoin.co/profile/nanspro

Language Technologies Research Centre (LTRC), Hyderabad, Telangana

Research Student

July 2018 - December 2018

I worked NLP related tasks such as Spell Corrector and Grammar Checker, did paraphrase detection on twitter also using popular distances like minkowski, euclidean, jaccard etc

Virtual Labs, Hyderabad, Telangana

Software engineer

August 2017 - November 2017

As part of my course Structured System Analysis and Design in IIIT, i worked with a client V-LEAD to develop a labdata services dashboard in django and vue-js

- The Project's aim was to design a user friendly dashboard for lab data services.
- We developed it as an SPA (Single Page Application) using plain JavaScript without any composite frameworks
 which allows manipulation of code to incorporate any features within the limit of the language and not just any
 framework
- Also used Vue-Js for front end which will get implemented on live website in future.

Professional Skills



Javascript

Python

Typescript

Ethereum

Blockchain

Smart Contracts

Operating System

Node.js

Artificial Intelligence

Algorithms

NLP

MIPS

C++

Software Development

Computer Networks

Flask/Django

Graphics, OpenGL/WebGL

Principles of Information Security

Strutured System Analysis and Design

Digital Signal Analysis and Applications

Database Modelling, Solr, Lucene, MySQL

Data Structures

Interesting Projects and Gigs

My personal projects done in college and my open source contributions. Code is open sourced and on github, links to them can be found on my linkedin.

Open Source

Pegasys

I worked on hobbits (a modular client for eth2.0 network testing) implementation in python.

Currently i am working on integrating it with trinity

LeapDAO

Implemented inflight-transaction(limbo) exits on plasma chain for leapdao organisation.

Also worked upon the solevem-enforcer repo and added a state function there to match the onchain and offchain computation state.

Chainstack

I wrote a tutorial for getting started with Chainstack, a cloud and protocol-agnostic platform that enables enterprises to rapidly deploy and manage blockchain applications.

I wrote a simple dapp for generating and verifying academic certificates on ethereum and deploying them to remote

chainstack nodes.

Unstoppable Domains

Added support for domain name services such ass ENS, ZNS, RNS in moonlet wallet

Ethereum

Removed special conditions of handling pre blocks from YUL optimizer in solidity

Ocean Protocol

I created bots for token distribution of Ocean Protocol on platforms such as twitter and telegram.

Plasma Group

Precompiling contracts to to use ENV variables in Vyper so that every time when a decoder is needed it'll generate it in vyper using environment variables.

UI/UX Improvements in Gitcoin

I have worked on various issues to improve UX for the wsbsite. Some of them are listed below:

Added Girly Hairstyles

Added Price Estimation functionality

Status

I completed three bounties of status, an organisation which is working on Ethereum based messaging app, building the first mobile-native-client in the language Nim.

I suggested moving from swig to nunjucks and then worked upon that.

Also added better rendering format like graphs, math, flow, sequence.using EJS

Fossasia

Badgeyay is a simple badge generator with a simple web UI to add data and generate printable badges in a zip.

I worked as a admin/maintainer of the repo and scaled it from a simple python scripts to a full functioning web app.

Ethhub

ETHHub provides information about what is going on inside ethereum and stuff.

I updated the ETH1.x docs by adding info about it's roadmap, need, working groups etc.

I also updated their docs to provide more information about ETH2.0 specs and roadmap and usage etc.

Personal

Distributed Quiz App

An online Quiz app with sophisticated state restore using smart contracts written in solidity

Auction on EVM

An advanced auction contract written in Vyper and solidity both.

Extreme Tic-Tac-Toe

A tic-tac-toe bot using complex AI methods and algorithms.

Tunnel Rush

A tunnel rush game written in web-gl.

Pacman Killer

A Mario like open world game with some physics included like motion in gravity, projectile.

Linux Shell

An interactive shell written in C as a part of Operating Systems Assignment - nanspro/Shell

Course Review Portal

A portal where students can rate their professors and their courses.

Achievements

- Gitcoin Rank #13 worldwide
- JEE Mains Rank 3245 out of 1.8 million students
- Got 1281 rank in JEE Advance out of 0.15 million students who passed the cutoff of JEE Mains
- Was part of TEDx organising team in Hyderabad
- Prithvi House skit Coordinator.